

MOHIT RATHORE

RED HAT CERTIFIED SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR
RED HAT CERTIFIED ENGINEER
PROGRAMMER | SYSTEM ENGINEER | DEVOPS ENGINEER

Mobile Number: 9584641272, 7999048960

Address: N1251, 3rd Floor, SBI Building, Kodigehalli Main Road, Bhadrappa Layout, Bangalore - 560094(KA)

Email: mohit.rathore74@gmail.com, mohitrathore.ratz@gmail.com **LINKEDIN:** https://in.linkedin.com/in/mohit-rathore-38ab40103

Birth-date: 12-12-1995

Sex: Male

Marital Status: Single Nationality: Indian

OBJECTIVE

Result oriented professional with 2.9 years of experience as a Devops Engineer, looking for a change to explore more challenging opportunity in a reputable organization to utilize my technical and management skills for growth of the organization.

SKILLS

Languages: C/C++, Java (J2SE), HTML/CSS, Python, Shell Scripting (Bash), YAML.

Operating Systems: Linux Distributions (RHEL, Fedora, CentOS, Ubuntu), Windows (XP, 7, 8, 10). **Softwares:** MySQL, Eclipse, Visual Studio, Android Studio, MS Office, CA-Service desk, RSA Archer.

Technologies: Data Structure and Algorithms, Software Engineering.

Devops Tools: Openstack, Docker, Kubernetes, GitHub, Jenkins, Ansible, AWS, Nagios.

WORK EXPERIENCE

DEVOPS ENGINEER Sept 2018 - Present

IDEMIA, Bangalore

Full Time

- Working in the project at client location "Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) Data Center, Bangalore".
- My work role is Linux System Administration, Scripting or Automation of tasks using **Bash** and **Python**, troubleshooting, Server Security, Biometric Data Analysis and Monitoring of servers and applications.
- Upgrade OS, firmware, McAfee and Application patches on more than thousand servers when it is required.
- Configure and manage storage, networks and cronjobs in production environment.
- Managed Server Migration & Consolidation Activity to utilize the infrastructure.
- Validate Disaster Recovery and Backup Restore Data to maintain data consistency.
- Implement solutions to fix vulnerabilities on servers and resolve it on Archer tool.
- Hands-on experience in version control system GIT.
- Hands-on experience in automating build process and CI/CD using Jenkins.
- Hands-on experience in automating configuration management and deployment using **Ansible.**

- Hands-on experience in virtualization using **Openstack**.
- Hands-on experience in containerization using **Docker** & **Kubernetes**.
- Monitored Production & System health using monitoring tools like **Ganglia** and **Nagios**.
- Communicate with clients for server & cloud operations, troubleshooting and hardware replacement.
- Hands-on experience on **AWS** Services like Amazon EC2, S3, Lambda, EBS, ECS, EKS, IAM, CloudWatch, CloudFront, CloudFormation, Auto-scaling and ELB.

TRAININGS

• Completed Training courses on AWS, Jenkins, Ansible, Docker and Kubernetes at Udemy. 2019-20 Hands-on training

• Major Training: Red Hat – Virtualization (Cloud Computing - IAAS)

2018

Hands-on training

• Minor Training: Python Programming

2017

Hands-on training

PROJECTS

• Automated Biometric Identification System (AADHAAR Project):

2018-present

It provides biometric services for UIDAI. It matches biometric data of newly enrolled candidates with the existing data from the database that involves Insertion, Identification and verification and removes duplicate candidates (de-duplication). This is a java application and it uses zookeeper, rabbitMQ and Scribe Server. Tested this application on OpenStack and Vmware, also deployed in docker containers.

Deployed this application on thousands of physical servers using Ansible.

Scale-up and Scale-down servers as per requirement.

Monitor and Maintain production with 100% uptime.

• Open Source Virtualization Management Platform:

2017

It is an infrastructure as a service cloud platform.

It can provide on demand scalable services like storage, networks, virtual machines, disk, and volumes to the clients from the clusters of data center.

Used Kernel-based Virtual Machine, RHEV-M management server, Ovirt engine and Virtualization technology to build a cloud on the Linux-based operating system.

Similarly, Configured cloud environment in openstack, openshift and Vmware.

• Sessional and Marksheet Generator:

2015-16

I have used java file management and Apache POI API

It has three modules Sessional, Marksheet, Detained list.

Sessional and detained list takes .xls file as input and generates .xls output.

Marksheet takes .xls file as input and creates doc file as output.

CERTIFICATIONS/ACHIEVEMENTS

• IDEMIA - Employee Appreciation Award 2020

Appreciated for leading and managing UIDAI Project

• RED HAT CERTIFIED ENGINEER (RHCE)

2016-12-02 CERTIFICATE NUMBER: 160-208-278

• RED HAT CERTIFIED SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR (RHCSA)

2016-10-06 CERTIFICATE NUMBER: 160-208-278

• SRIJAN 2015 - Software Innovative Model (State Level Competition).

Cleared regional round and won Consolation Prize in the final round.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING - COMPUTER SCIENCE 2014-2018

Lakshmi Narain College of Technology, Bhopal Secured: 74.3%

HIGHER SECONDARY CERTIFICATE (HSC) - 12th Class 2014

Ideal Higher Secondary School, Bhopal Secured: 70.2%

SECONDARY SCHOOL CERTIFICATE (SSC) - 10th Class 2012

Ideal Higher Secondary School, Bhopal Secured: 70.5%

CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Coding Competition: Game of Codes (Reached in final round) at LNCT College.

Clash of Codies (Reached in final round) at SISTECH College.

Code Enigma at LNCT College.

Appointy Hackathon 1.0 (Top 10 Programmer)

Cognizant MasterCode (AIR-3044) TCS Codevita2015, TCS Codevita2016.

Paper Presentation: A Review-On Cloud Computing.

Dance: Performed at cultural fest in many colleges and office events.

Singing: Performed at cultural fest in many colleges.

Fashion Show: Performed at tech and cultural fest SHRISHI 2016. **Marathon**: Completed 11km Marathon-Run Bhopal Run 2015 and 2016.